University of Connecticut, Athletic Communications Office Records 1999.0054
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, Athletic Communications Office Records
undated, 1894-2010
1999.0054
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
218.65 Linear feet
The office is responsible for the creation and distribution of information pertaining to University athletics. It began as a department within the Office of Public Information, Sports Information.
University of Connecticut. Athletic Communications Office.
University of Connecticut.
History
Established in the Office of Public Information as the Office of Sports Information, the responsibilities were transferred to the Division of Athletics in the 1970s.
Scope and Content
The collection contains publications, media guides, statistics, correspondence, press releases, clippings and similar materials associated with athletics at the University of Connecticut.
Arrangement
Note: only the information on archery and baseball has been integrated into this collection. Please contact the curator for information on other University affiliated sports.
The materials are arranged by sport and chronologically therein.
Archery ( 1946, 1952 )
Baseball ( undated, 1896-2003 )
Basketball (Men) ( undated, 1947-2011 )
Basketball (Women) ( undated, 1974-2011 )
Cross Country (Men) ( 1954-1996 )
Cross Country (Women) ( 1978-2003 )
Fencing ( 1949-1962 )
Field Hockey (Women) ( 1974-2003 )
Football ( undated, 1894-2010 )
Golf ( 1931-2003 )
Gymnastics ( 1975-1987 )
Ice Hockey (Men) ( 1961-2003 )
Lacrosse (Women) ( 1974-2003 )
Polo ( 1973-1976 )
Rifle ( 1949-1966 )
Rowing (Women) ( 2003 )
Rugby ( 1962 )
Skiing ( 1957-1978 )
Soccer (Men) ( 1928-2003 )
Soccer (Women) ( 1979-2005 )
Softball ( 1975-2003 )
Squash ( 1958-1961 )
Swimming and Diving (Men) ( 1930-2003 )
Swimming and Diving (Women) ( 1976-2000 )
Tennis (Men) ( 1910-2003 )
Tennis (Women) ( 1975-2000 )
Track and Field (Men) ( undated, 1949-2003 )
Track and Field (Women) ( 1975-2001 )
Volleyball (Women) ( 1975-2003 )
Wrestling ( undated, 1960-1980 )
Main Files ( undated, 1939-2009 )
Clippings Files ( 1988-2006 )
Programs ( undated, 1930-2006 )
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Dee Rowe 1999-0054.vr107
UConn Vs. UMass, 1938; UConn vs Maine, 1940 1999-0054.vr108
Acquisition Information
The records were transferred originally from the Office of Public Information. Subsequent additions have been transferred from the Athletic Communications Office.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
University of Connecticut; Administrative Records.; Correspondence.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Newspapers.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Photocopies.; Press releases.; Publications.; Storrs (Conn.)
- Archery, 1946, 1952
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes information on Eastern Archery Association and the 25th Olympic Bowman League.
  - 1946, 1952 (Box 10)
- Baseball, undated, 1896-2003
  This series includes information on the Freshman, JV, and Varsity teams from 1896-2003 including program brochures, publications, scorebooks, statistics, press releases, and batting and fielding records. It also includes information on collegiate conferences attended, including the Yankee Conference as well as the NCAA from 1949-1998.
  - 1896-1962 (Box 1)
  - Program brochures
  - Publications
  - Scorebooks
  - Statistics
  - Press releases
  - Scores
  - Yankee Conference
  - NCAA
  - Greater Boston Collegiate Baseball League
  - Dixie Classic
  - American Association of College Baseball Coaches
  - 1962-1971 (Box 2)
  - Hall of Fame
  - Clinic
  - 1968-1970 (Box 10)
  - 1971-1976 (Box 3)
  - College World Series
  - Cape Cod League
  - 1976-1983 (Box 4)
  - Eastern College Athletic Conference
  - College World Series
  - 1983-1990 (Box 5)
  - Big East
  - 1990-1994 (Box 6)
  - 1994-1998 (Box 7)
  - Opponents, 1896-1971
  - Records, 1935-1990 (Box 8)
  - Scorebooks, 1950-1983
  - Scorebooks, 1984-1986 (Box 9)
  - Unsorted Newspaper clippings, 1981-1986
  - Scorebooks, 1965-1979 (Box 11)
  - Scorebooks, 1980-1984 (Box 12)
  - Scorebooks, 1985-1987 (Box 13)
  - Scorebooks, 1988-1990 (Box 14)
  - Scorebooks, 1991-1995 (Box 15)
  - Scorebooks, 1996-2003 (Box 16)
- Basketball (Men), undated, 1947-2011
  This series includes items such as press releases, boxscores, freshman information, weekly records, statistics, schedules, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1947-2011, though this may not be inclusive. It also includes information on collegiate conferences attended, including the NCAA and Big East tournament.
  - Opponents (Box 66)
  - Opponents, 1998-1999 (Box 65)
  - Opponents, 1902-1953 (Box 64)
  - 1953-1961 (Box 63)
  - 1961-1968 (Box 62)
  - 1968-1972 (Box 61)
  - 1972-1977 (Box 60)
  - 1978-1982 (Box 59)
  - 1982-1987 (Box 58)
  - 1987-1990 (Box 57)
  - 1990-1992 (Box 56)
  - 1992-1997 (Box 55)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 54)
  - 1999 (Box 53)
  - 1999-2001 (Box 52)
  - Articles, 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Articles, 2000-2001 (Box 42)
  - Articles, 2001 (Box 43)
  - Articles, 2001-2002 (Box 44)
  - Articles, 2002-2003 (Box 45)
  - Articles, 2003 (Box 46)
  - Articles, 2004 (Box 47)
  - Articles, 2004-2005 (Box 48)
  - Articles, 2005 (Box 49)
  - Articles, 2006 (Box 50)
  - Articles, 2006-2007 (Box 51)
  - 2010-2011 (Box 2011-0056_2)
- Basketball (Women), undated, 1974-2011
  This series includes items such as press releases, boxscores, statistics, schedules, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1974-2011.It also includes information on collegiate conferences attended, including the NCAA and Big East tournament.
  - 1974-1988 (Box 35)
  - 1988-1991 (Box 36)
  - 1991-1993 (Box 37)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - 1995-1999 (Box 39)
  - 1999-2003 (Box 40)
  - Articles, 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - Articles, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Articles, 2000-2001 (Box 19)
  - Articles, 2001 (Box 20)
  - Articles, 2001-2002 (Box 21)
  - Articles, 2002-2003 (Box 22)
  - Articles, 2003 (Box 23)
  - Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 24)
  - Articles, 2004-2005 (Box 25)
  - Articles, 2005 (Box 26)
  - Articles, 2005 (Box 27)
  - Articles, 2005-2006 (Box 28)
  - Articles, 2006 (Box 29)
  - Articles, 2006 (Box 30)
  - Articles, 2006 (Box 31)
  - Articles, 2006-2007 (Box 32)
  - Articles, 2007 (Box 33)
  - Articles, 2007 (Box 34)
  - 2010-2011 (Box 184)
- Cross Country (Men), 1954-1996
  This series includes items such as press releases, statistics, schedules, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1954-1996.
  - 1954-1996 (Box 89)
- Cross Country (Women), 1978-2003
  This series includes items such as press releases, statistics, schedules, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1978-2003, though is not inclusive.
  - 1978-1991 (Box 89)
  - 1994-2003 (Box 90)
- Fencing, 1949-1962
  This series includes items such as press releases, scores, records and championships ranging in years from 1949-1962.
  - 1949-1962 (Box 87)
- Field Hockey, 1974-2003
  This series includes items such as press releases, statistics, schedules, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1974-2003, though is not inclusive.
  - 1974-1991 (Box 87)
  - 1991-2003 (Box 88)
- Football, undated, 1894-2010
  This series includes items such as press releases, boxscores, statistics, schedules, opponents, awards, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1894-2010. It also includes information on the 100 years of football, the upgrade to Division I, and collegiate conferences attended, including the NCAA and the Yankee Conference. Programs for individual games are arragned chronologically and date from 1928-1989.
  - Upgrade to Division I (Box 67)
  - Opponents (Box 68)
  - undated, 1894-1960 (Box 69)
  - 1957-1964 (Box 70)
  - 1965-1971 (Box 71)
  - 1972-1975 (Box 72)
  - 1975-1978 (Box 73)
  - 1977-1980 (Box 86)
  - 1979-1984 (Box 74)
  - 1980-1982 (Box 85)
  - 1984-1987 (Box 75)
  - 1987-1989 (Box 76)
  - 1989-1994 (Box 77)
  - 1994-1999 (Box 78)
  - 1996-1999 (Box 85)
  - Articles, 1992-1993 (Box 79)
  - Articles, 1994-1998 (Box 80)
  - Articles, 1998-2002 (Box 81)
  - Articles, 2002-2003 (Box 82)
  - Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 83)
  - Articles, 2004-2006 (Box 84)
  - Fiesta Bowl, 2010 (Box 183)
- Golf, 1931-2000
  This series includes items such as press releases, schedules, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1931-2003, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1931-1981 (Box 91)
  - 1982-2003 (Box 92)
- Gymnastics, 1975-1987
  This series includes items such as press releases, schedules, rosters and tournaments ranging in years from 1975-1987, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1975-1987 (Box 93)
- Ice Hockey, 1961-2003
  This series includes items such as press releases, schedules, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1961-2003, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1961-1973 (Box 94)
  - 1974-1979 (Box 95)
  - 1979-1992 (Box 96)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 97)
  - 1993-1995 (Box 98)
  - 1996-2003 (Box 99)
- Lacrosse, 1974-2003
  This series includes items such as press releases, schedules, rosters, scores, publicity forms, and news clippings ranging in years from 1974-2003, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1974-2003 (Box 100)
- Polo, 1973-1976
  This series includes items such as press releases, letters and news clippings ranging in years from 1973-1976.
  - 1973-1976 (Box 101)
- Rifle, 1949-1966
  This series includes items such as press releases, schedules, records and scores ranging in years from 1949-1966, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1949-1966 (Box 101)
- Rowing, 2003
  This series includes news clippings from 2003.
  - 2003 (Box 101)
- Rugby, 1962
  This series includes items press releases from 1962.
  - 1962 (Box 101)
- Skiing, 1957-1978
  This series includes items such as press releases, rosters, schedules and information on the Squaw Valley Olympics ranging in years from 1957-1978, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1957-1978 (Box 101)
- Soccer (Men), 1928-2003
  This series includes items such as press releases, rosters, statistics and news clippings ranging in years from 1959-2003, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1928-1980 (Box 102)
  - 1980-1987 (Box 103)
  - 1987-1995 (Box 104)
  - 1995-2003 (Box 105)
- Soccer (Women), 1979-2005
  This series includes items such as press releases, statistics, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1979-2005, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1979-1994 (Box 106)
  - 1997-2005 (Box 107)
- Softball, 1975-2003
  This series includes items such as press releases, scorebooks, rosters, statistics and news clippings ranging in years from 1990-2001, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1975-1987 (Box 107)
  - 1987-1994 (Box 108)
  - 1995-2003 (Box 109)
- Squash, 1958-1961
  This series includes items such as national rankings, opponents, and scores.
  - 1958-1961 (Box 109)
- Swimming (Men), 1930-2003
  This series includes items such as rosters, results, news articles and scores.
  - 1930-1995 (Box 110)
  - 1995-2003 (Box 111)
- Swimming (Women), 1976-2000
  - 1976-1991 (Box 111)
  - 1991-2000 (Box 112)
- Tennis (Men), 1910-2003
  This series includes items such as tournaments, results, news articles and scores.
  - 1910-2003 (Box 113)
- Tennis (Women), 1975-2000
  - 1975-2000 (Box 114)
- Track (Men), undated, 1949-2003
  This series includes items such as press releases, results, news articles and scores, records and information on indoor and outdoor teams as well as Yankee Conferences. The dates of this series range from 1949-2003, but may not be inclusive.
  - undated, 1949-1983 (Box 115)
  - 1984-2003 (Box 116)
- Track (Women), 1975-2000
  This series includes items such as results, news articles and scores, and team records.
  - 1975-1994 (Box 117)
  - 1994-2001 (Box 118)
- Volleyball, 1975-2003
  This series includes items such as press releases, schedules, rosters and news clippings ranging in years from 1975-2003, though this may not be inclusive.
  - 1975-2000 (Box 119)
  - 2000-2003 (Box 120)
- Wrestling, undated, 1960-1980
  This series includes items such as press releases, rosters publicity forms ranging in years from 1960-1980, inlcuding the 1973 Yankee Conference.
  - undated, 1960-1980 (Box 120)
- Main Files, undated, 1939-2009
  - 1939-1962 (Box 121)
  - 1946-1960 (Box 122)
  - 1949-1981 (Box 123)
  - 1949-1973 (Box 124)
  - 1955-1981 (Box 125)
  - 1957-1978 (Box 126)
  - 1957-1981 (Box 127)
  - 1961-1967 (Box 128)
  - 1962-1965 (Box 129)
  - 1965-1968 (Box 130)
  - 1968-1971 (Box 131)
  - 1970-1972 (Box 132)
  - 1972-1980 (Box 133)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 134)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 135)
  - 1976-1978 (Box 136)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 137)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 138)
  - 1981-1983 (Box 139)
  - 1983-1985 (Box 140)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 141)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 142)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 143)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 144)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 145)
  - 1990 (Box 146)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 147)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 148)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 149)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 150)
  - 1994 (Box 151)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 152)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 153)
  - 1996 (Box 154)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 155)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 156)
  - 1998 (Box 157)
  - 1999 (Box 158)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 159)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 160)
  - 2001 (Box 161)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 162)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 163)
  - 2003 (Box 164)
  - 2003-2004 (Box 165)
  - 2004-2005 (Box 166)
  - 2005 (Box 167)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 168)
  - 2006-2007 (Box 169)
  - 2007-2008 (Box 170)
  - 2008 (Box 171)
  - 2008-2009 (Box 172)
  - Athlete cards, 1929-1988 (Box 205)
- Clippings File, 1988-2006
  This series includes general clippings of most sports ranging from 1988 to 2006.
  - 1988-1993 (Box 173)
  - 1993-1999 (Box 174)
  - 1997-2001 (Box 175)
  - 2001-2006 (Box 176)
- Programs, undated, 1930-2006
  This series is arranged alphabetically by sport and then chronologically therein.
  - Baseball-Women's Basketball (Box 177)
  - Field Hockey-Football (Box 178)
  - Football (Box 179)
  - Football, 1928-1952 (Box 187)
  - Football, 1953-1955 (Box 188)
  - Football, 1956-1959 (Box 189)
  - Football, 1960-1962 (Box 190)
  - Football, 1963-1965 (Box 191)
  - Football, 1966-1969 (Box 192)
  - Football, 1970-1972 (Box 193)
  - Football, 1973-1974 (Box 194)
  - Football, 1975-1976 (Box 195)
  - Football, 1977-1981 (Box 196)
  - Football, 1982-1989 (Box 197)
  - Football, AIC - Boston University (Box 198)
  - Football, Brown - Holy Cross (Box 199)
  - Football, Navy - Rhode Island (Box 200)
  - Football, Kent State - Massachusetts (Box 201)
  - Football, Rhode Island - Rutgers (Box 202)
  - Football, Rutgers - Wesleyan (Box 203)
  - Football, Yale (Box 204)
  - Football-Men's Soccer (Box 180)
  - Men's Soccer-Volleyball (Box 181)
  - Soccer, 1977-1988 (Box 186)